Atmospheric Sciences and Research Center; Records ua450
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
Atmospheric Science Research Center Records
2014 October 17 - 2017 May 17
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
Atmospheric Science Research Center
ua450
6.5 cubic ft.
96 captures
The collection consists of inactive records from the University at Albany's Atmospheric Science Research Center.
Administrative History
The University at Albany established the Atmospheric Sciences Research Center (ASRC) on February 16, 1961, as a SUNY system-wide resource for developing and administering programs in basic and applied sciences related to the atmospheric environment. Founded by Vincent Schaefer, a General Electric protge of Nobel Prize winner Irving Langmuir, ASRCs world-class researchers study the physical and chemical nature of the atmosphere and apply that knowledge to explore the interaction of chemical, physical, geological and biological processes that impact our environment. Through technology transfer and collaboration with state, federal and industrial partners, ASRC enhances New York States scientific capacity and infrastructure, while advancing the quality of life and economic well-being of its citizens. ASRC is currently located in the CESTM (Center for Emerging Sciences & Technology Management) of the SUNY Albany campus. Research and development at ASRC spans a broad spectrum of scientific areas, including: advanced sensor development; laboratory and field experiments in atmospheric chemistry, atmospheric physics, and aerosol microphysics; remote sensing of the environment; global aerosol forecasting, air quality, climate change, and dispersion modeling; and high performance computing, scientific computing, and visual analytics. In 1975 the the Atmospheric Sciences Research Center began a project of creating a strustucre that uses minimal energy through creative architectural choices. They tested different kinds of wall construction and other unusual aspects of hoem construction to conserve as much energy as possible.
Scope and Contents
The collections consists of University at Albany's Atmospheric Science Research Center records including: annual reports, 1970-1983; programs of the center, 1970-1984; and publications, 1961-1984. There is also a series dedicated to the Minimum Energy Building project spearheaded by the Center from 1975-1979. This includes the various proposals of the project and reports on various tests done on the building.
Arrangement of the Collection
The collection is arranged into three topical series.
Acquisition Information
All items in this manuscript group were transferred to the University Libraries, M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives.
Related Materials
Related collections in the M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives can be found in the subject guide for Criminal Justice and Prisons.
Access
Access to this collection is restricted because it is unprocessed. Portions of the collection may contain recent administrative records and/or personally identifiable information. While it is likely that portions of the collection may be viewed, access must be managed by an archivist.
Conservation and the Environment; Web Archives; UAlbany Centers & Institutes; Wages -- New York (State); State University of New York at Albany-Atmospheric Sciences Research Center
- Department Website, 2014 October 17 - 2017 May 17; 1; 96 captures
  URL
  www.albany.edu/atmos
  Access Requirements
  The item contains web archives preserved as WARC files. They must be access though web archival replay tools such as the "Wayback Machine." The links here direct you to files hosted by the Internet Archive, but you may also request WARC files.
  Immediate Source of Acquisition
  Web crawling is managed through the Internet Archive's Archive-It service.
  This item is not a seed within an Archive-it collection, but capures of this page are found within:
  collection: University at Albany, SUNY Website
  created_date: 2012-09-17T13:15:00Z
  created_by: bkeough
  state: ACTIVE
  last_updated_date: 2016-09-26T23:38:05Z
  last_updated_by: system
  Web Collection
  - Internet Archive Wayback Machine, 2014 October 17
    This item had no crawl rules.
    The CDX index for this capture did not contain crawl information.
  - WARC file for Internet Archive Wayback Machine, 2014 October 17
    Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
    Researchers interested in data analysis with web archives may request a WARC file. WARC files are very large and difficult to work with. Your request may take time to process, and we may be unable to deliver your request remotely. Please consult an archivist if you are interested in advanced research with web archives.
  - Department of Atmospheric and Environmental Sciences - Meteorology - - University at Albany-SUNY, 2014 November 21
  - WARC file for Department of Atmospheric and Environmental Sciences - Meteorology - - University at Albany-SUNY, 2014 November 21
  - Department of Atmospheric and Environmental Sciences - Meteorology - - University at Albany-SUNY, 2014 November 29
  - WARC file for Department of Atmospheric and Environmental Sciences - Meteorology - - University at Albany-SUNY, 2014 November 29
  - Department of Atmospheric and Environmental Sciences - Meteorology - - University at Albany-SUNY, 2014 December 4
  - WARC file for Department of Atmospheric and Environmental Sciences - Meteorology - - University at Albany-SUNY, 2014 December 4
  - Department of Atmospheric and Environmental Sciences - Meteorology - - University at Albany-SUNY, 2014 December 12
  - WARC file for Department of Atmospheric and Environmental Sciences - Meteorology - - University at Albany-SUNY, 2014 December 12
  - Department of Atmospheric and Environmental Sciences - Meteorology - - University at Albany-SUNY, 2014 December 19
  - WARC file for Department of Atmospheric and Environmental Sciences - Meteorology - - University at Albany-SUNY, 2014 December 19
  - Department of Atmospheric and Environmental Sciences - Meteorology - - University at Albany-SUNY, 2015 January 2
  - WARC file for Department of Atmospheric and Environmental Sciences - Meteorology - - University at Albany-SUNY, 2015 January 2
  - Department of Atmospheric and Environmental Sciences - Meteorology - - University at Albany-SUNY, 2015 January 9
  - WARC file for Department of Atmospheric and Environmental Sciences - Meteorology - - University at Albany-SUNY, 2015 January 9
  - Department of Atmospheric and Environmental Sciences - Meteorology - - University at Albany-SUNY, 2015 January 23
  - WARC file for Department of Atmospheric and Environmental Sciences - Meteorology - - University at Albany-SUNY, 2015 January 23
  - Department of Atmospheric and Environmental Sciences - Meteorology - - University at Albany-SUNY, 2015 January 30
  - WARC file for Department of Atmospheric and Environmental Sciences - Meteorology - - University at Albany-SUNY, 2015 January 30
  - Department of Atmospheric and Environmental Sciences - Meteorology - - University at Albany-SUNY, 2015 February 6
  - WARC file for Department of Atmospheric and Environmental Sciences - Meteorology - - University at Albany-SUNY, 2015 February 6
  - Department of Atmospheric and Environmental Sciences - Meteorology - - University at Albany-SUNY, 2015 February 13
  - WARC file for Department of Atmospheric and Environmental Sciences - Meteorology - - University at Albany-SUNY, 2015 February 13
  - Department of Atmospheric and Environmental Sciences - Meteorology - - University at Albany-SUNY, 2015 February 19
  - WARC file for Department of Atmospheric and Environmental Sciences - Meteorology - - University at Albany-SUNY, 2015 February 19
  - Department of Atmospheric and Environmental Sciences - Meteorology - - University at Albany-SUNY, 2015 March 20
  - WARC file for Department of Atmospheric and Environmental Sciences - Meteorology - - University at Albany-SUNY, 2015 March 20
  - Department of Atmospheric and Environmental Sciences - Meteorology - - University at Albany-SUNY, 2015 April 2
  - WARC file for Department of Atmospheric and Environmental Sciences - Meteorology - - University at Albany-SUNY, 2015 April 2
  - Department of Atmospheric and Environmental Sciences - Meteorology - - University at Albany-SUNY, 2015 April 6
    This crawl was performed by the Internet Archive, not the UAlbany web archiving program, so the provenance is unknown.
  - Department of Atmospheric and Environmental Sciences - Meteorology - - University at Albany-SUNY, 2015 April 10
  - WARC file for Department of Atmospheric and Environmental Sciences - Meteorology - - University at Albany-SUNY, 2015 April 10
  - Department of Atmospheric and Environmental Sciences - Meteorology - - University at Albany-SUNY, 2015 April 16
  - WARC file for Department of Atmospheric and Environmental Sciences - Meteorology - - University at Albany-SUNY, 2015 April 16
  - Department of Atmospheric and Environmental Sciences - Meteorology - - University at Albany-SUNY, 2015 April 24
  - WARC file for Department of Atmospheric and Environmental Sciences - Meteorology - - University at Albany-SUNY, 2015 April 24
  - Department of Atmospheric and Environmental Sciences - Meteorology - - University at Albany-SUNY, 2015 May 1
  - WARC file for Department of Atmospheric and Environmental Sciences - Meteorology - - University at Albany-SUNY, 2015 May 1
  - Department of Atmospheric and Environmental Sciences - Meteorology - - University at Albany-SUNY, 2015 May 7
  - WARC file for Department of Atmospheric and Environmental Sciences - Meteorology - - University at Albany-SUNY, 2015 May 7
  - Department of Atmospheric and Environmental Sciences - Meteorology - - University at Albany-SUNY, 2015 May 22
  - WARC file for Department of Atmospheric and Environmental Sciences - Meteorology - - University at Albany-SUNY, 2015 May 22
  - Department of Atmospheric and Environmental Sciences - Meteorology - - University at Albany-SUNY, 2015 June 4
  - WARC file for Department of Atmospheric and Environmental Sciences - Meteorology - - University at Albany-SUNY, 2015 June 4
  - Department of Atmospheric and Environmental Sciences - Meteorology - - University at Albany-SUNY, 2015 June 12
  - WARC file for Department of Atmospheric and Environmental Sciences - Meteorology - - University at Albany-SUNY, 2015 June 12
  - Department of Atmospheric and Environmental Sciences - Meteorology - - University at Albany-SUNY, 2015 June 19
  - WARC file for Department of Atmospheric and Environmental Sciences - Meteorology - - University at Albany-SUNY, 2015 June 19
  - Department of Atmospheric and Environmental Sciences - Meteorology - - University at Albany-SUNY, 2015 July 19
    crawl: 165088
    Crawl Times
    start_date: 2015-07-17T16:55:07Z
    original_start_date: 2015-07-17T16:55:07Z
    last_resumption: None
    processing_end_date: 2015-07-22T22:02:18Z
    end_date: 2015-07-22T21:28:19Z
    elapsed_ms: 448383534
    Crawl Types
    type: MONTHLY
    recurrence_type: MONTHLY
    pdfs_only: False
    test: False
    Crawl Limits
    time_limit: 432000
    document_limit: None
    byte_limit: None
    crawl_stop_requested: None
    Crawl Results
    status: FINISHED_TIME_LIMIT
    discovered_count: 518483
    novel_count: 22064
    duplicate_count: 310947
    resumption_count: 0
    queued_count: 185472
    downloaded_count: 333011
    download_failures: 280
    warc_revisit_count: 310940
    warc_url_count: 332912
    total_data_in_kbs: 92321075
    duplicate_bytes: 89386949991
    warc_compressed_bytes: 975896456
    Crawl Technical Details
    doc_rate: 0.74
    kb_rate: 205.0
  - WARC file for Department of Atmospheric and Environmental Sciences - Meteorology - - University at Albany-SUNY, 2015 July 19
  - Department of Atmospheric and Environmental Sciences - Meteorology - - University at Albany-SUNY, 2015 August 19
    crawl: 169175
    start_date: 2015-08-17T16:54:59Z
    original_start_date: 2015-08-17T16:54:59Z
    processing_end_date: 2015-08-22T17:22:04Z
    end_date: 2015-08-22T16:57:37Z
    elapsed_ms: 432154021
    discovered_count: 580375
    novel_count: 18815
    duplicate_count: 281416
    queued_count: 280144
    downloaded_count: 300231
    download_failures: 232
    warc_revisit_count: 281408
    warc_url_count: 300140
    total_data_in_kbs: 104928074
    duplicate_bytes: 100253233235
    warc_compressed_bytes: 965534609
    doc_rate: 0.69
    kb_rate: 242.0
  - WARC file for Department of Atmospheric and Environmental Sciences - Meteorology - - University at Albany-SUNY, 2015 August 19
  - Department of Atmospheric and Environmental Sciences - Meteorology - - University at Albany-SUNY, 2015 September 19
    crawl: 173356
    start_date: 2015-09-17T16:57:20Z
    original_start_date: 2015-09-17T16:57:20Z
    processing_end_date: 2015-09-23T01:24:03Z
    end_date: 2015-09-23T00:16:53Z
    elapsed_ms: 458363239
    discovered_count: 367719
    novel_count: 26001
    duplicate_count: 206766
    queued_count: 134952
    downloaded_count: 232767
    download_failures: 237
    warc_revisit_count: 206761
    warc_url_count: 232678
    total_data_in_kbs: 101606587
    duplicate_bytes: 94029637527
    warc_compressed_bytes: 157865634
    doc_rate: 0.51
    kb_rate: 221.0
  - WARC file for Department of Atmospheric and Environmental Sciences - Meteorology - - University at Albany-SUNY, 2015 September 19
  - Department of Atmospheric and Environmental Sciences - Meteorology - - University at Albany-SUNY, 2015 October 18
    crawl: 179047
    start_date: 2015-10-17T16:56:32Z
    original_start_date: 2015-10-17T16:56:32Z
    processing_end_date: 2015-10-22T19:45:11Z
    end_date: 2015-10-22T19:02:36Z
    elapsed_ms: 439557452
    discovered_count: 390211
    novel_count: 36614
    duplicate_count: 202550
    queued_count: 151047
    downloaded_count: 239164
    download_failures: 276
    warc_revisit_count: 202548
    warc_url_count: 239075
    total_data_in_kbs: 61075441
    duplicate_bytes: 53769145120
    warc_compressed_bytes: 6127282356
    doc_rate: 0.54
    kb_rate: 138.0
  - WARC file for Department of Atmospheric and Environmental Sciences - Meteorology - - University at Albany-SUNY, 2015 October 18
  - Department of Atmospheric and Environmental Sciences - Meteorology - - University at Albany-SUNY, 2015 November 19
    crawl: 183657
    start_date: 2015-11-17T17:41:09Z
    original_start_date: 2015-11-17T17:41:09Z
    processing_end_date: 2015-12-03T05:50:07Z
    end_date: 2015-11-30T19:18:26Z
    elapsed_ms: 432098049
    discovered_count: 415196
    novel_count: 17867
    duplicate_count: 229881
    queued_count: 167448
    downloaded_count: 247748
    download_failures: 242
    warc_revisit_count: 229876
    warc_url_count: 247648
    total_data_in_kbs: 61913750
    duplicate_bytes: 62091532709
    warc_compressed_bytes: 256259119
    doc_rate: 0.57
    kb_rate: 143.0
  - WARC file for Department of Atmospheric and Environmental Sciences - Meteorology - - University at Albany-SUNY, 2015 November 19
  - Department of Atmospheric and Environmental Sciences - Meteorology - - University at Albany-SUNY, 2015 December 19
    crawl: 187970
    start_date: 2015-12-17T16:55:04Z
    original_start_date: 2015-12-17T16:55:04Z
    processing_end_date: 2015-12-22T21:57:26Z
    end_date: 2015-12-22T21:40:44Z
    elapsed_ms: 449129872
    discovered_count: 304232
    novel_count: 13877
    duplicate_count: 191764
    queued_count: 98591
    downloaded_count: 205641
    download_failures: 234
    warc_revisit_count: 191759
    warc_url_count: 205547
    total_data_in_kbs: 60257781
    duplicate_bytes: 60588343215
    warc_compressed_bytes: 34726906
    doc_rate: 0.46
    kb_rate: 134.0
  - WARC file for Department of Atmospheric and Environmental Sciences - Meteorology - - University at Albany-SUNY, 2015 December 19
  - Department of Atmospheric and Environmental Sciences - Meteorology - - University at Albany-SUNY, 2016 January 18
    crawl: 191947
    start_date: 2016-01-17T16:55:00Z
    original_start_date: 2016-01-17T16:55:00Z
    processing_end_date: 2016-01-22T17:27:17Z
    end_date: 2016-01-22T16:56:58Z
    elapsed_ms: 432114027
    discovered_count: 573952
    novel_count: 20681
    duplicate_count: 273347
    queued_count: 279924
    downloaded_count: 294028
    download_failures: 181
    warc_revisit_count: 273342
    warc_url_count: 293928
    total_data_in_kbs: 63947333
    duplicate_bytes: 64312716410
    warc_compressed_bytes: 176478309
    doc_rate: 0.68
    kb_rate: 147.0
  - WARC file for Department of Atmospheric and Environmental Sciences - Meteorology - - University at Albany-SUNY, 2016 January 18
  - Department of Atmospheric and Environmental Sciences - Meteorology - - University at Albany-SUNY, 2016 February 17
    crawl: 196723
    Crawl Rules
    Ignore Robots.txt for www.albany.edu (last updated 2016-02-11)
    Ignore Robots.txt for www.alumni.albany.edu (last updated 2016-02-11)
    Ignore Robots.txt for www.ualbanysports.com (last updated 2016-02-11)
    Ignore Robots.txt for library.albany.edu (last updated 2017-05-19)
    Ignore Robots.txt for alumni.albany.edu (last updated 2016-02-11)
    Ignore Robots.txt for asrc.albany.edu (last updated 2016-02-11)
    Ignore Robots.txt for atmos.albany.edu (last updated 2016-02-11)
    Ignore Robots.txt for bioinformatics.albany.edu (last updated 2016-02-11)
    Ignore Robots.txt for cela.albany.edu (last updated 2016-02-11)
    Ignore Robots.txt for choose.albany.edu (last updated 2016-02-11)
    Ignore Robots.txt for cs.albany.edu (last updated 2016-02-11)
    Ignore Robots.txt for csda.albany.edu (last updated 2016-02-11)
    Ignore Robots.txt for imls.ctg.albany.edu (last updated 2016-02-11)
    Ignore Robots.txt for www.ctg.albany.edu (last updated 2017-05-19)
    Ignore Robots.txt for cwig.albany.edu (last updated 2016-02-11)
    Ignore Robots.txt for events.albany.edu (last updated 2016-02-11)
    Ignore Robots.txt for hr.albany.edu (last updated 2016-02-11)
    Ignore Robots.txt for ibl.albany.edu (last updated 2016-02-11)
    Ignore Robots.txt for illiad.albany.edu (last updated 2016-02-11)
    Ignore Robots.txt for liblogs.albany.edu (last updated 2017-05-19)
    Ignore Robots.txt for libguides.library.albany.edu (last updated 2016-02-11)
    Ignore Robots.txt for scholarsarchive.library.albany.edu (last updated 2016-02-11)
    Ignore Robots.txt for listserv.albany.edu (last updated 2016-02-11)
    Ignore Robots.txt for m.albany.edu (last updated 2016-02-11)
    Ignore Robots.txt for math.albany.edu (last updated 2016-02-11)
    Ignore Robots.txt for omega.math.albany.edu (last updated 2016-02-11)
    Ignore Robots.txt for mumford.albany.edu (last updated 2016-02-11)
    Ignore Robots.txt for nyjm.albany.edu (last updated 2016-02-11)
    Ignore Robots.txt for pdp.albany.edu (last updated 2016-02-11)
    Ignore Robots.txt for resnet.albany.edu (last updated 2016-02-11)
    Ignore Robots.txt for rit.albany.edu (last updated 2016-02-11)
    Ignore Robots.txt for cyberphysics.rit.albany.edu (last updated 2016-02-11)
    Ignore Robots.txt for rna.albany.edu (last updated 2016-02-11)
    Ignore Robots.txt for slsc.albany.edu (last updated 2017-05-19)
    Ignore Robots.txt for uaems.albany.edu (last updated 2016-02-11)
    Ignore Robots.txt for uapps.albany.edu (last updated 2016-02-11)
    Ignore Robots.txt for wiki.albany.edu (last updated 2016-02-11)
    start_date: 2016-02-17T16:57:12Z
    original_start_date: 2016-02-17T16:57:12Z
    processing_end_date: 2016-02-23T04:10:10Z
    end_date: 2016-02-22T23:20:27Z
    elapsed_ms: 454987781
    discovered_count: 7638127
    novel_count: 795824
    duplicate_count: 806868
    queued_count: 6035435
    downloaded_count: 1602692
    download_failures: 248
    warc_revisit_count: 806856
    warc_url_count: 1602561
    total_data_in_kbs: 226292461
    duplicate_bytes: 193554304269
    warc_compressed_bytes: 633147239
    doc_rate: 3.52
    kb_rate: 497.0
  - WARC file for Department of Atmospheric and Environmental Sciences - Meteorology - - University at Albany-SUNY, 2016 February 17
  - Department of Atmospheric and Environmental Sciences - Meteorology - - University at Albany-SUNY, 2016 February 17
  - WARC file for Department of Atmospheric and Environmental Sciences - Meteorology - - University at Albany-SUNY, 2016 February 17
  - Department of Atmospheric and Environmental Sciences - Meteorology - - University at Albany-SUNY, 2016 March 17
    crawl: 201840
    start_date: 2016-03-17T16:54:59Z
    original_start_date: 2016-03-17T16:54:59Z
    processing_end_date: 2016-03-22T18:02:10Z
    end_date: 2016-03-22T16:56:57Z
    elapsed_ms: 432107388
    discovered_count: 639552
    novel_count: 138564
    duplicate_count: 332568
    queued_count: 168420
    downloaded_count: 471132
    download_failures: 1411433
    warc_revisit_count: 332563
    warc_url_count: 471037
    total_data_in_kbs: 116820623
    duplicate_bytes: 113225737713
    warc_compressed_bytes: 765920585
    doc_rate: 1.09
    kb_rate: 270.0
  - WARC file for Department of Atmospheric and Environmental Sciences - Meteorology - - University at Albany-SUNY, 2016 March 17
  - Department of Atmospheric and Environmental Sciences - College of Arts and Sciences - University at Albany - SUNY, 2016 April 17
    crawl: 207692
    start_date: 2016-04-17T16:55:13Z
    original_start_date: 2016-04-17T16:55:13Z
    processing_end_date: 2016-04-22T22:29:09Z
    end_date: 2016-04-22T18:00:08Z
    elapsed_ms: 435852385
    discovered_count: 7165982
    novel_count: 582992
    duplicate_count: 879835
    queued_count: 5703155
    downloaded_count: 1462827
    download_failures: 284
    warc_revisit_count: 879824
    warc_url_count: 1462700
    total_data_in_kbs: 227675763
    duplicate_bytes: 214936501775
    warc_compressed_bytes: 813502772
    doc_rate: 3.36
    kb_rate: 522.0
  - WARC file for Department of Atmospheric and Environmental Sciences - College of Arts and Sciences - University at Albany - SUNY, 2016 April 17
  - Department of Atmospheric and Environmental Sciences - College of Arts and Sciences - University at Albany - SUNY, 2016 May 17
    crawl: 212937
    start_date: 2016-05-17T16:55:02Z
    original_start_date: 2016-05-17T16:55:02Z
    processing_end_date: 2016-05-24T10:38:52Z
    end_date: 2016-05-22T22:20:27Z
    elapsed_ms: 451503421
    discovered_count: 8685839
    novel_count: 568136
    duplicate_count: 1043240
    queued_count: 7074463
    downloaded_count: 1611376
    download_failures: 229
    warc_revisit_count: 1043205
    warc_url_count: 1611247
    total_data_in_kbs: 246906729
    duplicate_bytes: 230750229955
    warc_compressed_bytes: 2352496320
    doc_rate: 3.57
    kb_rate: 546.0
  - WARC file for Department of Atmospheric and Environmental Sciences - College of Arts and Sciences - University at Albany - SUNY, 2016 May 17
  - Department of Atmospheric and Environmental Sciences - College of Arts and Sciences - University at Albany - SUNY, 2016 June 17
    crawl: 220038
    start_date: 2016-06-17T16:55:03Z
    original_start_date: 2016-06-17T16:55:03Z
    processing_end_date: 2016-06-23T01:46:32Z
    end_date: 2016-06-22T19:28:00Z
    elapsed_ms: 441165235
    discovered_count: 8887536
    novel_count: 557229
    duplicate_count: 1067492
    queued_count: 7262815
    downloaded_count: 1624721
    download_failures: 247
    warc_revisit_count: 1067450
    warc_url_count: 1624592
    total_data_in_kbs: 251943396
    duplicate_bytes: 239433481575
    warc_compressed_bytes: 1787914405
    doc_rate: 3.68
    kb_rate: 571.0
  - WARC file for Department of Atmospheric and Environmental Sciences - College of Arts and Sciences - University at Albany - SUNY, 2016 June 17